Finding Aid for School of Public Health (University of Michigan) Publications 1920-[Ongoing]
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
School of Public Health (University of Michigan) publications
1920-[ongoing]
University of Michigan. School of Public Health.
Contains bulletins (college catalogs); directories including the Photographic Roster; manuals; newsletters such as Findings, Public Health Reviews, and The School of Public Health Newsletter; proceedings from the Baker Lectures; programs including the Thomas Francis, Jr. Memorial Lecture; and reports including the Dean's Report, Report of the School of Public Health, Report of the Division of Hygiene and Public Health, A Self Study of the University of Michigan School of Public Health, Report to the Kellogg Foundation. Also contains publications from the Bureau of Public Health Economics including the Medical Care Review, Public Health Economics, Public Health Economics and Medical Care Abstracts, and research series reports. Also contains publications from the Dept. of Epidemiology including reports from the Poliomyelitis Vaccine Evaluation Center. Includes publications of the Dept. of Population Planning; the National Sanitation Foundation; Office of Development and Alumni Relations; Office of Development and External Relations; Office of Student Affairs including Student Enrollment and Application Information statistics; the Program in and Bureau of Hospital Administration; Program in Hospital Administration; the Public Health Library. Also includes bulletins for the Summer Session and student publications.
9713 Bimu C281 2
11 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
Publications are received periodically from the unit (Donor no. 1756 )
The publications are open for research.
See the history in the finding aid for the School of Public Health (University of Michigan) Records.
The Publications of the School of Public Health are divided into four series: Unit Publications, Sub-Unit Publications, Topical Publications and Student Publications. Some publications (or their successors) may no longer be available in print but are available on the school s website.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Dept. of Hospital Administration.; University of Michigan. Program in Hospital Administration.; University of Michigan. Division of Hygiene and Public Health.; University of Michigan. Bureau of Public Health Economics.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Epidemiology.; University of Michigan. Poliomyelitis Vaccine Evaluation Center.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Population Planning.; National Sanitation Foundation (U.S.); University of Michigan--Alumni and alumnae.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs.; University of Michigan. School of Public Health.
Contributors:
University of Michigan. Bureau of Public Health Economics.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Epidemiology.; University of Michigan. Poliomyelitis Vaccine Evaluation Center.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Population Planning.; National Sanitation Foundation (U.S.); University of Michigan. Summer Session.; University of Michigan. Program in Hospital Administration.; University of Michigan. Division of Hygiene and Public Health.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Hospital Administration.
Publications:
Photographic roster.; School of Public Health newsletter.
Genre/Form:
Bulletins.; Directories.; Manuals.; Newsletters.; Proceedings.; Programs.; Reports.; Statistics.; Student publications.
- Unit Publications
  Unit Publications include bulletins, and long runs of the newsletters Findings and the School of Public Health Newsletter. The student directory, Photographic Roster, is available from 1960 through 1972. There is also a faculty Photographic Roster for the years 1969, 1979, and 1982. Also included are Self-Study reports for the years 1975, 1980 and 1985 and the Dean's Report which spans the period from 1960-1985.
  - Addresses
    - Dedicatory Address, 1944 (Box 1)
  - Bibliographies
    - Cancer Education: An Annotated Bibliography, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Brochures
    - Miscellaneous (Includes departmental brochures), undated; 1954-1992; 2002-2003; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Bulletins (Degree Program Requirements)
    - General Bulletin
      - 1941-1989, 14 folders (Box 1)
      - 1991/92-2004/05, undated; 10 folders (Box 10)
      - Degree Requirements, 2007-2009; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Courses in Hygiene, Public Health and Preventive Medicine
      - 1928/29-1937/38 (Box 1)
    - Graduate Programs in Public Health
      - 1922/23-1937/38 (Box 1)
    - Programs for Study: Professional Education of Public Health Personnel
      - 1937/38-1940/41 (Box 1)
    - Public Health Nursing
      - 1920-1921 (Box 1)
  - Directories
    - Directory of Academic Information and Services, undated (Box 1)
    - Photographic Roster (Faculty), 1969/70 (Box 1)
    - Photographic Roster (Faculty), 1979; 1982; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Photographic Roster, 1960/61-1971/72; 12 folders (Box 1)
      (includes Enrollment Lists)
    - Photographic Roster (Box 2)
      - 1972/73-1982/83, 10 folders (Box 2)
      - 1986/87-1991/92, 6 folders (Box 2)
      - 1994-1995 (Box 2)
      - 1997-1998 (Box 2)
      - 1999-2003 (Box 2)
  - Lectures
    - Dental Problems; Obvious, Overwhelming, Overlooked, 1962 (Box 2)
    - Principals of Industrial Hygiene, 1931 (Box 2)
  - Manuals
    - Degree Programs, undated (Box 2)
    - Student Guide to Admissions, Financial Aid and Student Services, undated (Box 2)
    - Through the Knothole (Box 2)
  - Newsletters
    - Findings
      - Volumes 1-16, 1986-2001; 15 folders (Box 2)
      - Vol. 17-, 2001- (Box 10)
    - Public Health Reviews
      - Volumes 1-10, 1932-1941; 2 volumes (Box 2)
    - School of Public Health Newsletter
      - 1941-1982, 21 folders (Box 2)
  - Proceedings
    - The Baker Lectures, 1962-1973 (Box 3)
    - The Citizens Public Health Conference, 1953 (Box 3)
    - Conference on Ethics, Humanism and Medicine, 1986 (Box 3)
    - Executive Process in Public Health Administration, 1966 (Box 3)
    - Health Conference for Public Officials, 1946 (Box 3)
    - Health Education in Cancer Control: Proceedings of the Seminar on Health Education in Uterine Cancer Programs, 1967 (Box 3)
    - Human Behavior, Motivation and Communication Processes, 1953 (Box 3)
    - Health Physics Society, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Housing Improvement, 1955 (Box 3)
    - The League Exchange: Report of Conference on Field Instruction in Public Health Nursing, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Lectures Presented at the Inservice Training Course in Refuse Collection and Disposal, 1947 (Box 3)
    - Lectures Presented at the Inservice Training Course on the Relation of Nutrition to Maternal and Child Health, 1946 (Box 3)
    - Man and His Environment: The Proceedings of the Second National Congress on Environmental Health, 1961 (Box 3)
    - Memorial Assembly: John Sundwall 1880-1950, 1951 (Box 3)
    - Proceedings of the Conference on Preventive Medicine and Health Economics, 1946 (Box 3)
    - Proceedings of the National Symposium on Quality Standards for Natural Waters, 1966 (Box 3)
    - Radioactive Liquid Wastes, 1955 (Box 3)
    - Radiological Health, 1951 (Box 3)
    - Towards the Evaluation of Population -- Environment Programs, 1998 (Box 3)
  - Programs
    - Convocation, 1977-2006 (Box 3)
    - International SARS Symposium: A Case Study for Public Health Preparedness, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Fortieth Anniversary of the Polio Vaccine, 1995 (Box 3)
    - Fifty Years at Michigan, 1991 (Box 3)
    - Health Issues in the Middle East, 1997 (Box 3)
    - National Symposium on Quality Standards for Natural Waters, 1966 (Box 3)
    - Ninth Conference on Ethics, Humanism, and Medicine, 1982 (Box 3)
    - Philosophy on Modern Health Services, 1950 (Box 3)
    - Portrait Unveiling, 1964 (Box 3)
    - Seminar on Health Education in Uterine Cancer Programs, 1967 (Box 3)
    - Testimonial Banquet, 1974 (Box 3)
    - Thomas Francis Jr. Memorial Lecture
      - 1970-1988 (Box 3)
  - Questionnaires
    - Health Behaviors Questionnaire, undated (Box 3)
  - Reports
    - Blocks to Attainment of Optimum Oral Health: A Survey of the Available Literature, 1955-56 (Box 3)
    - Dean's Report
      - 1960/61-1984/85, 6 folders (Box 3)
    - Faculty Conference on Curriculum Improvement, 1952 (Box 4)
    - A Faculty Responds: A Case Study of the School of Public Health, The University of Michigan, 1973 (Box 4)
    - Health Service in American Colleges and Universities, 1926 (Box 4)
    - Honor Roll of Donors, 2003 (Box 4)
    - Investigation and Application of Home Injury Survey Data in Development of Prevention Procedures, 1952-1953
      - Appendix A: Procedure Manual, 1953 (Box 4)
      - Appendix B: Environmental Appraisal, 1953 (Box 4)
    - Report of the Division of Hygiene and Public Health, 1928 (Box 4)
    - Report of the School of Public Health
      - 1941/42-1959/60, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Report to the Kellogg Foundation
      - 1941-1947, 5 folders (Box 4)
    - A Self-Study of the University of Michigan School of Public Health
      - 1975 (Box 4)
      - 1980 (Box 4)
      - 1985 (Box 5)
      - 1992 (Box 5)
      - 1999 (Box 5)
    - Small Business and Health Care Reform, 1994 (Box 5)
    - Summary of Public Health, Time Schedule, 1999-2000 (Box 5)
- Sub-Unit Publications
  Sub-Unit Publications consist of materials produced by units within the School of Public Health. These include the Bureau of Public Health Economics, which produced the newsletters Medical Care Review and Public Health Economics, as well as a Research Series of Reports. The materials from the Department of Epidemiology include reports from the poliomyelitis field trials of 1954. Other sub-units include the Department of Population Planning, the National Sanitation Foundation, the Office of Development and Alumni Relations and the Office of Student Affairs.
  - Bureau of Public Health Economics
    - Newsletters
      - Medical Care Review
        - Volumes 25-27, 1968-1970; 7 folders (Box 5)
        - Volumes 30-31, 1973-1974; 9 folders (Box 5)
      - Public Health Economics (Box 6)
        - Volumes 1-8, 1944-1951; 7 folders (Box 6)
        - Volumes 9-16, 1952-1959; 44 folders (Box 7)
      - Public Health Economics and Medical Care Abstracts
        - Volumes 21-22, 1964-1965; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Reports
      - Research Series no. 1-14
        - State Enabling Legislation for Non-Profit Hospital and Medical Plans, no. 1, 1944 (Box 7)
        - Administration of Medical Care; Problems and Issues, no. 2, 1947 (Box 7)
        - Emergency Maternity and Infant Care; A Study of Administrative Experience, no. 3, 1948 (Box 7)
        - Prepayment of Physician's Services for Recipients of Public Assistance in the State of Washington: Problems and Issues, no. 4, 1949 (Box 7)
        - Disability Compensation for the Disabled Sick, no. 5, 1949 (Box 8)
        - Hospitalization of the People of two Counties: A Study of the Experience in Hillsdale and Branch Counties 1942-1945, no. 6, 1949 (Box 8)
        - Michigan Nursing Facilities and their Patients: A Source Book of State and County Data, no. 8, 1960 (Box 8)
        - Malaria Eradication and Population Growth with Special Reference to Ceylon and British Guiana, no. 10, 1965 (Box 8)
        - Disability Insurance in California, no. 11, 1965 (Box 8)
        - Disability Insurance in California Supplement, 1965 (Box 8)
        - A Review of Some Experiences with Prepaid Group Practice, no. 12, 1965 (Box 8)
        - The Urban Aged: Race and Medical Care, no. 14, 1968 (Box 8)
    - Syllabus
      - Introduction to Public Health Economics, 1946 (Box 8)
  - Department of Biostatics
    - Reports
      - Biostatics Department 1994-1995 Report (Box 8)
  - Department of Environmental and Industrial Health
    - Archives of Environmental Health Vol. 21, 1970 (Box 8)
    - Programs
      - Environmental Health Discussional, 1986 (Box 8)
      - Selby Discussional on Occupational Medicine, 1985-1986 (Box 8)
    - Brochures, 1988-1990; undated (Box 8)
  - Department of Epidemiology
    - Poliomyelitis Vaccine Evaluation Center
      - Reports
        - Evaluation of the 1954 Field Trial of Poliomyelitis Vaccine, 1957 (Box 8)
        - An Evaluation of the 1954 Poliomyelitis Vaccine Trials: Summary Report, 1955 (Box 8)
  - Department of Health Behavior and Health Education
    - Newsletter
      - Pressure Points, undated (Box 8)
  - Department of Health Planning and Administration
    - Economic Impact of UM Medical Center, 1986 (Box 8)
    - Reports
      - Selected Policy Issues in Physician Distribution: A Resource Book, 1982 (Box 8)
  - Department of Health Services Management and Policy
    - Brochures and Miscellaneous
      - 1985, undated (Box 8)
    - Photo Rosters, 1993/94- 1994/95 (Box 8)
  - Department of Medical Care Organization
    - Brochures
      - 1970-1974 (Box 8)
  - Department of Population Planning
    - Brochures
      - 1966-1972, undated (Box 8)
  - Department of Population Planning (cont.)
    - Newsletter
      - Population and Fellows Program, 1995 (Box 8)
    - Reports
      - Reports Concerning Phase Out of the Department of Population Planning, 1976 (Box 8)
      - The World Health Organization and the Population Issue: Organizational Values in the United Nations, 1976 (Box 8)
  - Department of Public Health Statistics
    - Reports
      - An Investigation of the Causes of Home Accidents, 1952 (Box 8)
  - Health Education Program (Box 9)
    - Reports
      - Accountability in Health Education: A Report on an Afternoon Workshop, 1974 (Box 9)
  - Institute of Industrial Health
    - Annual Report, 1966/1967, 1994; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - National Sanitation Foundation
    - Reports
      - Report of the First National Sanitation Clinic, 1948 (Box 9)
      - Ten Year Report, 1945-1954 (Box 9)
  - Office of Career Services
    - Newsletter
      - Job Bulletin, 1991 (Box 9)
  - Office of Community and Government Relations
    - Newsletter
      - Community Connections, 1993-1994 (Box 9)
  - Office of Development and Alumni Relations
    - Brochures
      - Continuing the Mission: A Bridge to the Future, undated (Box 9)
    - Newsletters
      - The PHIB (Public Health Information Bulletin)
        - 1987-1989, undated (Box 9)
  - Office of Development and External Relations
    - Newsletter
      - Windows
        - 1990-1991, 1994-1996 (Box 9)
  - Office of Development and Government Relations
    - Brochures, 1985-2004 (Box 9)
  - Office of Student Affairs
    - Reports
      - A Strategy for Initiating the On Line Admission System for the Office of Student Affairs, 1989 (Box 9)
    - Statistics
      - Student Enrollment and Application Information
        - Fall Terms, 1980-1987 (Box 9)
        - Fall Terms, 1984-1988 (Box 9)
  - Program in Bureau of Hospital Administration
    - Michigan Hospital Performance Measures Project
      - Reports
        - HPM Seminar: Education Session for Trainers, 1978 (Box 9)
        - Quality Measures for Hospital Performance Measurement Reports, 1978 (Box 9)
  - Program in Hospital Administration
    - Brochures
      - 1971-1987, undated (Box 9)
  - Program in Hospital Administration Alumni Association
    - The Eclectic
      - 1968-1969, 1971; 1973-1996; 1998-1999 (Box 11)
  - Public Health Library
    - Catalogs
      - New Books and Periodicals, 1962 (Box 9)
      - Recent Accessions, 1944-1961 (Box 9)
    - Newsletters
      - SPH Library News, 1985 (Box 9)
      - Public Health Library News, 1993 (Box 9)
    - Reports
      - Annual Reports
        - 1963-1964 (Box 9)
  - The Resource for Public Health Policy
    - Reports
      - Licit/Illicit Substance Abuse Prevention Policy, 1987-1989 (Box 9)
- Topical Publications
  - Summer Session
    - Bulletins
      - Courses in Hygiene and Public Health
        - 1924-1944 (Box 9)
      - Public Health Nursing
        - 1919-1939 (Box 9)
      - Special Public Health Institutes
        - 1930-1932 (Box 9)
- Student Publications
  - General
    - Newsletters
      - The Handout
        - Volumes 1-2, 1969-1970; 2 folders (Box 9)
      - The Plague, 1984 (Box 9)
  - Individual
    - Public Health Student Association
      - Manuals
        - Hustler's Hand-Me-Down, 1972 (Box 9)
      - Newsletters
        - Sphocus, 1975 (Box 9)
- Archived School of Public Health Website
  The Archived Website series documents the academic programs, accomplishments, resources, events, and people at the School of Public Health. Content includes important news and announcements, publications (such as newsletters and course catalogs), and information about admissions, curriculum, degree requirements, faculty, and the overall mission of the School. The website series is arranged chronologically, with captures from 2002, 2003, and 2006 stored on CD. Starting in 2010, this archived website will be captured on a regular, ongoing basis as part of the University of Michigan Web Archives, hosted at http://webarchives.cdlib.org/a/universityofmichigan/.
  - Website capture, May 15, 2002; 1 optical disks CDs (Box 2)
  - Website capture, May 22, 2003; 1 optical disks CDs (Box 3)
  - Website capture, May 19, 2006 (Box 3)
  - Archived School of Public Health home page, 2010-[ongoing]
  - Archived websites related to the School of Public Health, 2010-[ongoing]